# USMAN ANWAR

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

LinkedIn | GitHub

VISA STATUS: Permanent Resident MOBILE #: 6476579153

E-MAIL: usmananwar@outlook.com

ADDRESS: Toronto, Ontario, Canada. M6E4V4

Seasoned Software Engineer experienced in developing applications, databases and cloud computing solutions. Smart professional with proven troubleshooting and debugging capabilities for resolving complex technical issues. Detail-oriented, organized and meticulous employee. Works at fast pace to meet tight deadlines. Enthusiastic team player ready to contribute to company success.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

**DP WORLD** | Seoul, South Korea

JULY 2020 - OCTOBER 2023

- Owned the "EDGE GATEWAY" modules of an IoT project.
- Design and developed scalable microservices to receive events/messages from hundreds of devices and process them in near real-time.
- Implemented services in Spring Boot and Spring Integration to support communication with IoT device over different communication protocols including HTTP and TCP/IP.
- Written different vendor specific messaging parsers to parse messages in Binary, JSON, XML formats.
- Setup duplication of incoming messages using "GoDuplicator" and routed them to a different server(UAT) for testing new features of the UAT server.
- Conducted stress testing with "¡Meter" for benchmarking.
- Involved in DevOps activities and setup Docker swarm clusters for Dev and Production environtment.
- Setup docker container monitoring tool "Portainer" to monitor the status of all containers.
- Setup "PostgreSql" relational database and "Timescale DB" for timeseries data.
- Maintained CI/CD and all the build process on Microsoft Azure using self-hosted agent.
- Maintained the maven proxy repositories.
- Prepared the documentation of containing all messages flow diagrams.

### **TECHNOLIGIES:**

Java8, Java11, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring Integration, Infinispan, Kafka, Swagger, PostMan, jMeter, Eclipse, DBeaver, PostgreSql, Docker Swarm, Microsoft Azure DevOps, DrawlO, Linux, Maven, Git, redmine, REST, Microservices

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

**IbizSoftware inc.** | Seoul, South Korea DECEMBER 2017 – JULY 2020

- Worked on a client's (Korean Air) project to migrate a monolithic system to a microservices architecture deployed on Amazon cloud.
- Specifically, focused on implementing a unified authentication system for various applications across different domains within Korean Air internal departments. This involved deploying OAuth 2.0 on Amazon Lambda and conducting a comparative analysis against a prototype using Amazon Cognito identity services.
- Involved in handling service logs and their storage in Amazon Kinesis service.
- Blockchain (Ethereum) related:
  - Worked a full stack developer for "Berith" platform using Angular and Spring Boot. The "Berith" is a platform offering blockchain based financial services to its customers; <a href="https://wallet.berith.co">https://wallet.berith.co</a>
  - Implemented "Nodejs" backend services to provide interface between Ethereum blockchain and the wallet app.
  - Worked on different project to automate the deployment of the Ethereum blockchain nodes (private/public).
  - o Management and configuration of internal private blockchain networks.

#### **TECHNOLIGIES:**

Java8, Java11, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, MariaDB, Mybatis, Elasticsearch, Redis, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, Nodejs, AWS EC2, AWS Kinesis, AWS Congnito, AWS Lambda, AWS pipelines, DrawlO, Linux, Maven, Git, Redmine, REST, MSA, OAuth2.0, Ethereum Blockchain, Parity, Geth, Smart Contracts, Truffle

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Namutech | Seongnam-si, South Korea

OCTOBER 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2017

- Modified a Java based open-source project, "OpenBaton", an ETSI MANO compliant project, for a client (Samsung network lab) for 5G Virtual Network Functions' (VNFs) orchestration demonstration.
- Implementation of Netconf protocol layer in the above-mentioned project.
- Automated the deployment of OpenStack instances.
- OpenStack configurations including PCI-pass-through, CPU pinning and NUMA cell allocation etc.
- Researched and consulted about the industry standards for describing VNFs, initialization of VNFs and handling lifecycle events, i.e. OASIS TOSCA, ETSI MANO, ETSI VNF Packaging specifications.

### **TECHNOLIGIES:**

Java8, Spring Boot, MariaDB, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, Linux, Maven, Git, RedHat, KVM, Virtual Machines, OpenStack.

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

i2c inc. | Lahore, Pakistan

DECEMBER 2013 - AUGUST 2014

- Frontend and Backend development for the in-house J2EE web applications responsible for the prepaid cards payment processing.
- Customization of web components of Struts 2.0 framework, for localization and validation support.
- Testing and debugging of payment processing applications.

### **TECHNOLIGIES:**

Java8, Spring Boot, Struts 2.0, JSPs, MariaDB, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, Linux, Maven, Git.

### JAVA DEVELOPER

All In One Technology | Lahore, Pakistan

**IUNE 2012 - DECEMBER 2013** 

- Worked as a full stack developer for responsible for the development of front and back-end development of project components.
- Reduced software bugs by conducting thorough unit testing and collaborating with QA teams.
- Developed user-friendly interfaces for web applications, improving user experience and satisfaction.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design, develop, and launch innovative software solutions.
- Ensured seamless integration of Java-based applications with databases, APIs, and other systems.

# **TECHNOLIGIES:**

Java7, Spring MVC, JSPs, JSF, Hibernate, MariaDB, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, Maven, Git, SVN

•	Java	•	JQuery	•	Git	•	Docker	•	Nodejs
•	Spring	•	HTML	•	SVN		Swarm	•	Truffle
	Framework	•	CSS	•	Jenkins	•	Linux	•	Azure
•	JSP/Servlet	•	MySql	•	Hibernate	•	Ethereum	•	AWS
•	Struts 2.0	•	Postgres	•	MyBatis	•	Parity		
•	JSF	•	Elastisearch	•	KAFKA	•	Geth		

**SKILLS** 

## **EDUCATION**

OpenStack

Web3j

## MASTER OF COMPUTER ENGINEERING

AJOU UNIVERSITY | Suwon, South Korea

**Javascript** 

SEPTEMBER 2014 - AUGUST 2016 GPA: 4.06/4.50

**PUBLICATIONS:** 

SAF: States Aware Fully Associative FTL for Multitasking Environment | SpringerLink

Redis

Log-buffer aware cache replacement policy for flash storage devices | IEEE Journals & Magazine | IEEE Xplore

# **BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE**

GOVERNMENT COLLEGE UNIVERSITY (GCU) | Lahore, Pakistan

SEPTEMBER 2008 - JUNE 2012 GPA: 3.31/4.00